greenweddingshoes.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy - Green Wedding Shoes

_Updated October 26, 2018_

We’ve recently updated both our Privacy Policy and [Terms of Service](https://greenweddingshoes.com/terms-of-service/) to improve transparency and communicate your control over your data.

  * **Transparency** **:  **We want to ensure you understand the type of data we collect from you, where we store it and how it’s safeguarded.
  * **Control** **:  **Your data is  **your** data. We’ve always treated it as such and will continue to do so. You have the ability to opt in and out of emails, correct inaccurate data, delete your data and, if you’re a vendor with a Green Wedding Shoes profile,  delete your account at any time.

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices of Green Wedding Shoes, LLC. and greenweddingshoes.com, our email newsletters and other applications owned and operated by Green Wedding Shoes, LLC. (collectively referred to as the “GWS Services”), and to any services that display this notice. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to “Green Wedding Shows” include greenweddingshoes.com.

The GWS Services may contain links to other websites for your convenience and information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites.

## What information do we gather about you?

The information gathered when you interact with the GWS Services falls into two categories:

  1. **Personal information:  **This includes personal information you supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, enter a contest, create a vendor profile, submit content for editorial consideration or provide your email address
  2. **Non-personal information:  **This information is collected through technology, which includes tracking information collected by us as well as third parties.

### Personal Information That You Give Us Or Ask a Third Party to Share with Us

#### **Billing and Credit Card Information**

To enable payment for GWS Services we collect and store name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card information and other billing information. This information will only be shared with third parties who help to complete the purchase transaction. Examples of this include fulfilling orders and processing credit card payments.

#### User Generated Content and Public Activities (Including Comments)

We offer you opportunities to engage in public activities on greenweddingshoes.com and other GWS Services. “Public activities” are any actions you take on greenweddingshoes.com that are designed to be visible to other users, including comments, submitting content to be considered for editorial features or any other items that you submit. Any information you disclose in your public activities, along with your screen name or ID, or any images or photos, becomes public and may be used by Green Wedding Shoes for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you choose to engage in public activities, you should be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, collected and used by other users of these areas. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in the course of your public activities and we have no responsibility to publish, take down, remove or edit any of your public activities or submissions. For more information, read the Forums, Discussions and User Generated Content section of the Terms of Service.

Public activities may be included in our RSS feeds and other distribution formats. As a result, your public activities may appear on other websites, blogs, feeds or social networks. Keep in mind that we are not responsible for any personal information you choose to make public via your public activities, and you agree that such sharing will be deemed to have been done by you, not Green Wedding Shoes.

When you share or recommend links to content on a third-party platform (including but not limited to Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, Google+ and Twitter), that action and any information you share will be covered by their privacy policy.

#### **Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers**

Green Wedding Shoes collects personal information from you when you participate in sweepstakes, contests or special offers. If this information is also being collected by a third party other than Green Wedding Shoes, we will notify you at the same time. If you do not want any personal information shared, you should not participate in the sweepstakes, contest or special offer.

#### **Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research**

Green Wedding Shoes may collect personal information from you in connection with voluntary surveys conducted via the GWS Services. Data may be collected through the GWS Services, on the phone or through the mail. The information you provide may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection.

Participants in our polls or discussions about their readership of Green Wedding Shoes, agree to voluntarily share information about their household/personal characteristics and their purchase behavior.

### Non-Personal Information Collected Using Technology

#### Information Collected by Us Using Technology

We use various internet technologies to manage the GWS Services and track use of the Services. Non-personal information that we collect using these technologies may be combined with other information about you.

**Device Information:**  We may collect non-personal information about the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access the GWS Services, such as IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language and other transactional information.

**Cookies, Beacons, Local Storage and Other Similar Technologies:**  We use “cookies,” web beacons, tags and scripts, and other similar technologies including local storage objects such as HTML5. These technologies allow us to manage access to and use of the Services, recognize you and provide personalization, and help us understand how people use the GWS Services. You may not be able to access certain areas of greenweddingshoes.com if your computer does not accept cookies from us. We do not respond to browser-based “do not track” signals.

We may transmit non-personally identifiable website usage information to third parties in order to show you advertising for Green Wedding Shoes when you visit other sites. For more information about our third-party ad server, or to learn your choices about not having this non-personal information used to target ads to you, please [click here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

#### **Local Storage Objects**

We may use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information.

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

#### **Analytics, Log Files and Reading History**

Like most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses (the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet), browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of the GWS Services, including a history of the pages you view.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, advertising, marketing, and to track access and use of the GWS Services across the devices that you use to access the GWS Services.

We have hired third parties to provide us information, reports and analysis about the usage, browsing patterns of our users. They may independently record the type of device and operating system you are using, general location information, as well as events that occur within our apps, such as how often you use our apps.

**Location Information:**  The ads on greenweddingshoes.com are not targeted to you based on your current GPS location, but they may be targeted to you based on your ZIP code or device’s IP address.

**Google Signals**

Google Analytics will associate the visitation information it collects from GWS Services with Google information from accounts of signed-in users who have consented to this association for the purpose of ads personalization. This Google information may include end user location, search history, YouTube history, and data from sites that partner with Google—and is used to provide aggregated and anonymized insights into users’ cross device behaviors. Your data may be accessed and/or deleted by end users via [My Activity](https://myactivity.google.com/myactivity).

#### **Third Parties**

Some of the services and advertisements included in the GWS Services, including on greenweddingshoes.com, are delivered or served by third-party companies, which may collect information about your use of the GWS Services.

These companies may place or recognize cookies, web beacons or other technology to track certain non-personal information about our website users. For example, in the course of serving certain advertisements, an advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser in order to collect certain information about your use of the GWS Services. For another example, an advertiser or ad server may also be able to collect your device’s unique identifier in the course of serving an ad. In many cases, this information could be used to show you ads on other websites based on your interests.

We do not have access to, nor control over, these third parties’ use of cookies or other tracking technologies or how they may be used.

Please click here to see a list of third parties that may be using cookies to serve advertising on our websites or in our apps. For example, we use Google to serve advertisements onto the GWS Services, which use the Google DoubleClick cookie, and in some cases, a unique device identifier, to show you ads based on your visit to greenweddingshoes.com and other sites on the internet. You may opt out of the use of the Google DoubleClick cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences).

You have choices about the collection of information by third parties on our website:

1) If you would like more about your option not to accept advertiser cookies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).

2) If you would like to opt-out of having interest-based ad targeting, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Your access to our websites should not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.

## What do we do with the information we gather about you?

### **Provide the Services You Request**

We use the information we gather about you to enable your use of the GWS Services and fulfill your requests for certain products and services, such as sending out electronic newsletters and enabling you to participate in and renew paid services, polls and contests.

### **Statistical Analysis**

We perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of users of the GWS Services, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our subscriber base. We use this information for analysis purposes, including analysis to improve customer relationships.

### **Customizing Your Experience**

We use the information that we collect to allow advertising to be targeted to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. We also use this information to customize certain features of the GWS Services to provide you with an enhanced experienced based on the type of device you are using to access the GWS Services, and in certain cases, provide you with requested services.

### **Relevant Advertising**

We may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising on the GWS Service to be targeted to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer’s experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We disclose information to third parties only in aggregate or de-identified form.

### **Email Newsletters**

Green Wedding Shoes will periodically send you email newsletters or promotional email about services offered byGreen Wedding Shoes and its advertisers.

## With whom do we share the information we gather?

### **Within Green Wedding Shoes**

If you have registered to use the GWS Services, we will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address without your permission.

In the future, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, we may include your information among the transferred assets.

### **Third Parties**

We also share information about our audience in aggregate or de-identified form. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to restrict our use or sharing of aggregated or de-identified information in any way.

We may share information about attendees to our live events with sponsors or other third parties. If so, we will notify you when you provide us the information.

### **Service Providers**

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, ad serving, shipping, email distribution, list processing and analytics or promotions management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using personal information in any way other than to provide services for Green Wedding Shoes, and they may not share, resell or use the data for their own direct marketing purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose your opt-out information to third parties so they can suppress your name from future solicitations, in accordance with applicable laws. We may occasionally release personal information as required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena. (For more information, see the “Compliance with Legal Process” section of this policy.)

## What is our email policy?

Green Wedding Shoes complies with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not send you marketing messages if you have opted out. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by either (1) following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each email, or (2) you can opt-out here. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address for commercial purposes without your permission. If you feel you have received an email from us in error, please contact [privacy@greenweddingshoes.com](mailto:privacy@greenweddingshoes.com).

**Email Newsletters:  **Green Wedding Shoes offers several email newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter.

**Survey Email.**  We may invite you to participate in user surveys asking for feedback on greenweddingshoes.com and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve the GWS Services, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.

**Emails From You.**  If you send us an email, we will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

## How do I opt-out?

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive email marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email.

If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [privacy@greenweddingshoes.com](mailto:privacy@greenweddingshoes.com) and provide your email address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe.

### Is my information protected?

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, technical and administrative controls to protect the information. Please note that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

## Other Infomation

### **Compliance With Legal Process  
**

We may access, preserve and disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the GWS Services; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

### **Children’s Guidelines**

**COPPA Compliance:  **Green Wedding Shoes does not knowingly collect or store any personal information about children under the age of 13.

**International Transfers:** Green Wedding Shoes is headquartered in the United States. The information you submit to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of the Services may be collected in your country and subsequently transferred to the United States or to another country so that we may provide you the Services.

U.S. law and the laws of other countries where we may store and process your information may offer different levels of protection for information than may be available in your country. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your information.

#### **Your California Privacy Rights**

Under the California “Shine The Light” law, California residents may opt-out of the GWS’s disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. As detailed above, you may choose to opt-out of the sharing of your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes at any time by submitting a request in writing to Customer Care, 1014 S Westlake Blvd #14-287, Westlake Village, CA 91361 or by emailing us at [privacy@greenweddingshoes.com](mailto:privacy@greenweddingshoes.com?subject=Opt-out). It is important to note that this opt-out does not prohibit disclosures made for non-marketing purposes.

### **Changes to This Policy**

We evaluate this privacy policy periodically in light of changing business practices, technology and legal requirements. As a result, it is updated from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use or share your personal information, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice within the Services at least 30 days prior to the changes taking effect.
